Om Shree

♥ Bangalore, India☑ om22shree@gmail.com┗ +91 8360195490in om22shree

IT undergrad passionate about Kubernetes, E2E automation, Linux and event streaming solutions. Demonstrated experience working DevOps roles in a fintech company with strict SLAs. Have a knack for developer velocity and scale. Supported and developed multiple production grade systems for low latency and high throughput critical financial data operations.

Certifications

- CKAD ☑ Certified Kubernetes Application Developer Linux Foundation
- GitOps at scale

 GitOps certification level 2 Codefresh
- System design **∠** Coding Ninjas

Education _____

BTech KIIT University, Information Technology

Sept 2020 - Sept 2024

- CGPA: 9.2/10 (engineering semester mark-sheets <a>I
- · Coursework: Algorithm Design, Computer Networking, OS, DBMS and ML

Experience _

FICO ☑, Cloud Engineer Associate

Global Platform Capabilities, Event Streaming

Bangalore
July 2024 - Present

- Automated deployment and patching of multiple production-grade StreamNative Pulsar clusters using nested Helm charts, GitHub shared workflows, EKS CSI drivers and ArgoCD
- Implemented Istio strict MTLS, function mesh DAG and DAPR pubsub for Pulsar on EKS
- Implemented observability for pulsar using OpenTelemetry and Grafana
- Implemented autoscaling for Pulsar broker and bookkeeper pods using HPA, KEDA and prometheus custom metrics
- On-call support, operations and monitoring improvements through AppDynamics for production Apache Kafka clusters using Cloudformation

FICO ☑, Cloud Engineer Intern

Global Platform Capabilities, AWS infrastructure

Bangalore June 2023 – June 2024

- Developed enterprise wide AWS account life-cycle management automation using Terraform,
 Boto3, Python3 and Jenkins
- Participated in CSA STAR level 2 and PCI attestation audit cloud infrastructure
- Responsible for enterprise enhancements, automations, maintenance and **on-call support** for all **Route53** records, **IAM** policies and **AWS organization** components
- Implemented enterprise AWS cost control policies through CloudHealth, lambda functions and SCPs
- Automated image and IAC scanning using GitHub workflows, Aquasec and KICS

Projects and Hobbies _

- Multiple **spot awards** throughout my tenure at FICO akin to performance incentives
- Make frequent pilgrimage to **Kubernetes** source codebase
- Pulsar visualizer to provide telemetry data for all topics in a cluster built using Streamlit, Python3 and Go